(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-05T01:35:24.613142",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のじゃー！
Noja~!
挨拶しますのじゃー！
Time for my greetings, noja~!
あちち！メラメラ！あちちメラ！
Achichi! Meramera! Achichi Meira!
ホロライブ、あそびまわりたいご利益担当のひのこのサラマンダー、あちちメラだのじゃー！
From Hololive's Asobi Mawari-tai, the fire child salamander in charge of blessings, Achichi Meira, noja~!
めっちゃエコーかかった。
The echo is really strong.
The echo is really strong!
今日は、あそびまわりたい歌枠リレーですのじゃー！
Today is the Asobi Mawari-tai singing relay, noja~!
簡単に、今日の流れをお主らに紹介しますのじゃ！よいしょ。
I'll briefly introduce today's schedule to you all, noja! Up we go.
20時から、わし、あちちメラ。
Starting at 20:00, me, Achichi Meira.
20時20分から、十蘭そあ。
From 20:20, Sorasina Soa.
20時40分から、涼海つづり。
From 20:40, Suzumi Tzuri.
21時から、千燈ゆうこ、それぞれ個人の枠で歌を歌いまして、
From 21:00, Chidou Yuuko. We will each sing on our individual channels.
そして最後に、21時20分、あちちメラチャンネルで全員集合コラボを行いますのじゃ！
And finally, at 21:20, we will hold a group collaboration stream on Achichi Meira's channel, noja!
今日のお主らの予定、決まったの？うむ。
Have you all decided on your schedule for today? I see.
そう、初配信順にしてみたのじゃー！
Yes, we arranged it in order of our debut streams, noja~!
今日ね、イベントの話とかも4人コラボの時にできたらいいなって思ってるので、
Today, I hope we can talk about the upcoming events during our four-person collab, so...
早速わしからお歌歌っていこうかの？
shall we start off with my singing right away?
1人20分じゃからね、わしがねゆっくり喋ってたらね、あとのね、みんなが歌えなくなっちゃうから、
Since each person only has 20 minutes, if I talk too slowly, the others won't have enough time to sing.
歌っていこうと思いますのじゃ！
So I'm going to get right to the singing, noja!
お主ら、全員のチャンネル登録と高評価をお忘れなくお願いしますのじゃー！
Everyone, please don't forget to subscribe to all of our channels and leave a like, noja~!
うむ、今日はおねだりなし。あの、お焦らしなし。なぜなら時間がパツパツじゃから。
Yup, no begging or teasing today. Because our schedule is super tight!
ということで、早速最初の曲、よいしょ。
With that said, let's move on to the first song! Up we go.
あれ、よいしょ...
Oh, up we go...
最初の曲はこちら！お主ら、聞きたかったじゃろ？聞きたかったじゃろ？
The first song is this one! You all wanted to hear this, right? You really did, didn't you?
わしが最初の「歌ってみた」で歌うかなって結構予想されてた、
A lot of people predicted I would sing this for my very first cover video...
「サラマンダー」という曲を歌わせていただきますのじゃ！ちょっと緊張するけど、頑張る、頑張る。緊張するのじゃ。いくのじゃ！
I will be singing the song "Salamander", noja! I'm a bit nervous, but I'll do my best. I'm really nervous. Here I go!
よいしょ。
Up we go.
サラマンダー
Salamander...
食い意地が良くない？ やっぱ ぱぱぱぱぱ 大問題？
Isn't greediness bad? As expected, pa-pa-pa-pa-pa, a big problem?
ねえ "炎"では良くなくない？ "もっと"が聞きたい 頭の中は最高更新中
Hey, isn't flame not good enough? I want to hear "more". My mind is constantly updating its peak.
サラマンダー
Salamander...
いっぱい欲しい クセになるなんて ずるくない？ ねえ？
I want a lot. Isn't it unfair that it becomes habit-forming? Right?
知ってたんなら 先に伝えておいてほしかったかな ねえ？
If you knew, I wish you had told me beforehand, right?
もう降参です ハマっちゃって 君なしじゃダメダメになっちゃって
I give up now, I'm completely hooked. I'm useless without you now.
リピっちゃいたい ビリっちゃいたい おかわりできるかな？ もう一回！
I want to repeat, I want to get shocked. Can I have a second helping? One more time!
サラマンダー 食い意地が良くない？ やっぱ ぱぱぱぱぱ 大問題？
Salamander, isn't greediness bad? As expected, pa-pa-pa-pa-pa, a big problem?
ねえ "炎"では良くなくない？ "もっと"が聞きたい 頭の中は最高更新中
Hey, isn't flame not good enough? I want to hear "more". My mind is constantly updating its peak.
更新中
...is being updated!
やめられないのよ
I just can't stop,
やめたくないのよ
I don't want to stop!
ちゃんとフゥーして
Blow on it properly,
火傷したくないなら
if you don't want to get burned.
緊張するのじゃ！
I'm so nervous!
いっぱい欲しい よだれとか
I want a lot, like my drool
ぱっちり止まらない
that won't stop running.
何回でも
No matter how many times,
メラメラになって仕上がりたい
I want to burn up and be complete.
生き急いじゃって
Living life in the fast lane,
あっちっち ちょい猫舌だからめんどくさい
it's hot! It's a pain because my tongue is sensitive.
リピっちゃいたい ピリっちゃいたい
I want to repeat it, I want that spicy kick,
おかわりできるかな もう1回
can I get a refill? Just one more time!
真っ赤に燃えてみたい
I want to burn bright red...
燃えたいのじゃ
I want to burn!
サラマンダー
Salamander!
愛！ホットが良くない？
Love! Isn't hot better?
やっぱぱぱぱ 大問題？
Is it really a big problem after all?
ねえ「だって」は良くなくない？
Hey, isn't saying "but" a bad thing?
“もっと”が聴きたい
I want to hear "more"!
頭の中はどうだい？
How's it going inside your head?
サラマンダー
Salamander!
ほっくに駄目じゃん
Leaving it alone is a no-go,
やっぱぱぱぱ 絶好調？
are you in top shape after all?
ねえ 正直なくなくない？
Hey, isn't honesty lacking?
本音が聴きたい
I want to hear your real feelings!
頭の中は最高更新中
Inside my head, the records are being updated!
やめられないのよ
I just can't stop,
やめたくないのよ
I don't want to stop!
ちゃんとフゥーして
Blow on it properly,
火傷したくないなら
if you don't want to get burned.
抜け出したいけど
I want to get out,
抜け出せないのよ
but I can't escape!
ちゃんとフゥーして
Blow on it properly,
火傷したくないなら
if you don't want to get burned.
サラマンダーでしたのじゃ！
That was Salamander!
お主ら、聞きたかったでしょう？
You guys wanted to hear it, right?
DECO*27さんのね、サラマンダーって曲。
DECO*27-san's song, Salamander.
プロセカとカップヌードルコラボの曲じゃったかな？
I think it was a Proseka and Cup Noodle collab song?
聞きたかった？聞きたかった？
Did you want to hear it? Did you want to hear it?
やったー！あっちっちとか言ってるしな。
Yay! Since it says "achicchi" and stuff.
いやー、トップバッター緊張する！
Ah, being the opening act is so nerve-wracking!
緊張するけど、
I'm nervous, but...
よいしょ、次の曲歌うのじゃ。
Alright, I'll sing the next song.
もうね、歌枠リレーとはね、
You see, singing relays are...
たくさん歌うもの。
...about singing lots of songs.
よいしょ。
Alright.
次の曲はこちら！
The next song is this!
アニソンも持ってきましたのじゃ！
I brought an anime song too!
「とまどい→レシピ」というアニソンを持ってきたのじゃ。
I brought an anime song called "Tomadoi Recipe."
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a moment.
これ。
This...
えっと…
Um...
あ、全部でわし、4曲歌う。
Oh, in total, I'm singing four songs.
わし4曲歌います。
I'll sing four songs.
行くのじゃ！
Here we go!
え、大丈夫かな？こんなゆっくりしてて大丈夫かな？
Is this okay? Is it okay to be so slow?
ちょっとゆっくりすぎる？
Am I being too slow?
あ、BGM…
Oh, the BGM...
歌うのじゃー！
I'm gonna sing!
初めて聞くお主らも、きっと好きになると思いますのじゃ！
Even if you're hearing it for the first time, I'm sure you'll love it!
ふっふー！らったったーらったらったーふっふー！
Fuh-fuh! Rattatta rattaratta fuh-fuh!
らったらったーいぇいいぇーい！
Rattaratta yay-yay!
らったったらったらったらーふっふー！いぇい！
Rattatta rattaratta fuh-fuh! Yay!
朝目が覚めたらもう
When I wake up in the morning,
昨日みたいな日常はなくて
my usual daily life is gone.
「ホントあぁもう…えっとどうしよう」
"Seriously, oh man... what should I do?"
ため息混じりに練る お菓子と妄想のレシピの中に
Sweets mixed with sighs, inside this delusional recipe...
恋心入っちゃった
...I accidentally put my love in it.
シフォンケーキに
Chiffon cake,
カスタード
custard,
スコーンに
scones,
クロテッドクリーム
clotted cream.
だけどやっぱそれっておかしいわ
But after all, that's just strange.
どうして私なんだろう
Why does it have to be me?
急にそんなこと言い出して…
Suddenly saying something like that...
あぁどうしよう
Oh, what should I do?
君を好きになっちゃうかなんてわからないけど
I don't know if I'll fall in love with you,
大切な人だなんて
but calling you my precious one...
あぁ照れくさいかな
...ah, is it too embarrassing?
君は真面目なトーンで「好き」ってなんて言うでしょう
In a serious tone, how would you say "I love you"?
ちょっとドキッとしちゃうじゃん
That makes my heart flutter a bit.
なんて非日常的なレボリューション
What an extraordinary revolution!
らったったらったらったらーふっふー！いぇい！
Rattatta rattaratta fuh-fuh! Yay!
どんな味が好きとか
What kind of flavors you like,
何が食べられないとか
what you can't eat...
知っといた方がいいかなってね
...maybe I should get to know those things?
ため息混じりに練る
Mixing it with sighs,
洋理のレシピの中に
inside the cooking recipe...
とまどいが入っちゃった
...I accidentally put my confusion in it.
プリンアラモード
Pudding à la mode,
モンブラン
Mont Blanc,
トキメクチョコレート
heart-fluttering chocolate.
だけどやっぱ…
But after all...
だけどやっぱこれっておかしいの
But really, isn't this strange?
どうして私赤いの
Why am I turning so red?
あの言葉を思い出して
Remembering those words you said...
もうどうしよう
Oh, what should I do?
君が好きって言ったって
Even if you say you love me,
どうしていいか分かんないよ
I don't know what to do!
秘密って言っても
Even if we call it a secret,
否定されたらちょっとショック
if you deny it, I'll be a little shocked.
君に思いきっちゃって
I'm going to take the plunge...
「ねぇ、あの」って呼び止めちゃった
and call out to you, "Hey, um..."
ちょっとドキッとしちゃうじゃん
It makes my heart skip a beat,
急に笑顔なんてしないでよ
so don't suddenly smile at me like that!
Go Love Win! Everybody let me GO!
It's show time now! Everybody let's GO!
Go Fight Win! Let me show me make me down.
Go Love Win! Take my heart!
Go Love Win! Everybody let me GO!
It's show time now! Everybody let's GO!
Go Fight Win! Let me show me make me down.
Go Love Win! GO GO GO GO GO!
のじゃ〜ん！
Noja~n!
のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ〜
Noja, noja, noja, noja~
君のその無表情な中に
Within that expressionless face of yours,
時々見えた笑顔とかがっかりとか あれ？探してるの？
sometimes I see a smile or disappointment... wait, am I looking for them?
君に思いきっちゃって
I'm going to take the plunge...
「ねぇ、あの」って呼び止めちゃった
and call out to you, "Hey, um..."
ちょっとドキッとしちゃうじゃん
It makes my heart skip a beat,
急に笑顔なんてしないでよ
so don't suddenly smile at me like that!
君を好きになっちゃうかなって
Will I end up falling in love with you?
分からないけど
I don't know,
大切な人だなんて
but to call you my "precious person"...
あー照れくさいかな
Ah, that's kind of embarrassing...
君は真面目なトーンで
In a serious tone,
「好き」だなんて言っちゃってさ
you said "I like you,"
ちょっとドキッとしちゃうじゃん
which makes my heart skip a beat!
なんて非日常的なレボリューション
What an extraordinary revolution!
恋の
A recipe...
レシピ
of love!
らったったらったらった ふぅふぅ
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, foo-foo!
らったったっぱ いぇいいぇい
Rat-ta-ta-pa, yay-yay!
らったったらったらった ふぅふぅ
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, foo-foo!
らったったっぱ いぇいいぇいいぇーい！
Rat-ta-ta-pa, yay-yay-yay!
はぁ〜、ふふふ、一人で歌うの大変じゃった〜
Phew... Hehe, singing all by myself is tough!
可愛かった？可愛かった？
Was it cute? Was it cute?
そっ、サラマンダーってこんな可愛い曲なんじゃよ、へへっ
See, "Salamander" is such a cute song! Hehe.
ありがとうなのじゃ、とまといレシピでしたのじゃ！
Thank you so much! That was "Tomatoi Recipe"!
はぁ〜、息を整えつつ...
Phew... catching my breath...
よいしょ
There we go.
もう一曲ボカロ曲をお持ちしましたのじゃ、あ、ちらっと見えちゃった。ちら、ちら、よいしょ
I've brought one more Vocaloid song. Oh, you saw a glimpse of it. Peeking, peeking... there we go.
次が、3曲目
Next is... the third song!
よいしょ
There we go.
お水飲むのじゃ
I'll drink some water.
ふぅ〜、落ち着いた。落ち着いたから歌うのじゃ
Phew, I feel calm now. Since I'm calm, I'll sing!
キャットラビングっていう曲を
A song called "Cat Loving"...
キャットラビングっていう曲を歌いますのじゃ、早速
I will sing "Cat Loving"! Let's get right into it!
行くのじゃ
Here we go!
よいしょ、よいしょ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ
There we go, there we go, noja, noja, noja.
行くのじゃ！
Here we go!
痛いことは嫌いですか？
Do you dislike painful things?
君の手の平は嫌いじゃない
But I don't dislike your palm.
言葉は飴玉みたいに
Your words are like candy,
甘く広がってココロ満たす
sweetly spreading and filling my heart.
ああ全然わかってない、永遠に言う通り、完全にフェアじゃない
Ah, you don't understand at all, I'll always do as you say, it's completely unfair.
どこにいても「おいで」は効いてない
No matter where I go, "come here" has no effect.
もともともっとあの子みたいに可愛くならなくちゃ
I originally had to become much cuter, just like that girl.
愛情は聡明に、証拠はHow many
Love must be wise, how many proofs are there?
もう大体痛いののだって分かんなくなる
I can't even tell anymore if it mostly hurts.
延命マタタビ、首にご褒美
Prolonging life with silver vine, a reward around the neck.
「もう嫌」になったって離されないように
So that I won't be let go, even if I get tired of it.
今日だってちゃんとね、内緒の毛づくろい
Today too, I'm doing my secret grooming properly.
良い子にするから愛して
I'll be a good girl, so love me.
Everybody, today is rubbing day.
Get it get it, this is my courtship.
Any any, anytime is fine with me.
Gimme gimme, love me, my darling.
会いたい、間違いなんて皆は言う
I want to see you, "that's a mistake" everyone says.
取り憑かれているって
Saying that I'm possessed.
ならこの胸で疼く
Then, this aching in my chest...
締め付けるような切なさは何なの？
What is this tightening painful sadness?
選ぶ言葉 戸惑う指先 端正な横顔
Choosing words, my hesitant fingertips, your handsome profile.
ランダムご機嫌 もしかして今日は優しく撫でてくれるのかな？
Your random moods... I wonder if today you will gently stroke my head?
君のそれが耐えられるの 生涯で私だけなんだよね
I'm the only one in my life who can tolerate that side of you, aren't I?
あからさまに カラダまさに 「もう嫌だ」って離れられないよね そうだよね？
Obvious as it is, my body is just like... "I've had enough," but we can't separate, right?
感情は徐々に 歌えは少々に
Emotions gradually rise, my singing voice just a little...
もうLieもサインのように 転がせばいい
Even lies are like a sign now, I should just let them roll.
柑橘の匂い 吐き出す残り香
Citrus scent, exhaled lingering scent...
もう噛んだって 叱られるだけだし
"Even if I bite, I'll just get scolded."
今日だってちゃんとお膝でおとなしく
Today too, I'll be good and stay on your lap...
にゃんってお好きなように完全淘汰して
saying "meow" just as you like, completely weeding out the rest.
キャットラビングでしたのじゃ！
That was "Cat Loving"!
猫ちゃんなのじゃ！にゃお〜ん！
I'm a kitty cat! Meow!
そして！次が最後の曲ですのじゃ！
And now! Next is the final song!
水、水、水、水、水、水、水。
Water, water, water...
やばい、時間がない、時間がないのじゃ。
Oh dear, there's no time left, we're out of time.
えっと、最後の曲は…主らも聴きたい人がいたんじゃないかのう？
Let's see, the last song is... I bet there are people who wanted to hear this, right?
Mela! あちちMela! なのだな。
"Mela!" It's "Mela!", burning hot.
よし、最後の曲、Mela! 歌いますのじゃい！よいしょ！
Alright, the last song, "Mela!", I'm going to sing it! Here we go!
ふん！
Yes!
いけるかな？
Will I be okay?
ふん！
Okay!
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる 眠っているだけの正義
The justice that is just sleeping, boiling and burning hot.
こんな僕も君の ヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero!
ラララ...
La la la...
かっこいい君には 僕じゃ頼りないのかなって
I wonder if I'm too unreliable for someone as cool as you.
そりゃそうだよね だって 今もこうして迷ってる
Well, that makes sense, since I'm still hesitating like this.
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero!
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden inside someone like me, boiling and burning hot,
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable urge...
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, before I knew it, I'm holding your hand.
いったい全体 そんなに荷物を
What on earth? Carrying so much baggage...
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
...where are you heading to?
ねえねえ待って  僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Hey, wait, why don't you try letting me carry some of it?
緊張がほぐれてきましたのじゃ。最後じゃけど。
I'm starting to relax now. Even though it's the last song.
信じてばかりの僕と 信じることが怖い君と
Me, who does nothing but trust, and you, who is afraid to trust...
どちらが正しいのかなんて 誰にも分からないさ
No one knows which of us is right.
僕らだけの世界 ギブとテイクさ
In a world of just the two of us, it's give and take.
補い合えた暁には 同じ夢を見たい
Once we make up for each other's flaws, I want us to see the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
Making you suffer because "you're cool" and leaving you all alone...
少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
That was a bit my fault, wasn't it? I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what we need to look at is reality!
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Right now, I will save you!
抱えないで 信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't carry it all alone, I want you to trust and rely on me.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't now the time?
メラメラとたぎる こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden inside someone like me, boiling and burning hot,
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable urge...
ほら気付けば手を握っている ほっておけない
Look, before I knew it, I'm holding your hand. I can't leave you alone!
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Carrying so much baggage, where are you heading to?
ほんのちょっと  僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Just a little bit, why don't you try letting me carry some of it?
ちょっと預けてみては？
...entrusting it to me?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero.
ラララ ラララ
La la la, la la la...
もうすぐ20分なので
It's almost 20 minutes past,
この曲でおしまいですのじゃー！
so this will be the last song!
おぬしら、4曲、乙知メラの歌枠を
Everyone, for listening to Ochichi Mela's...
聴いてくれてありがとうなのじゃー！
...4-song singing stream, thank you so much!
じゃーん！
Tada!
ありがとうございましたのじゃ！
Thank you very much!
これで乙知メラの歌枠はおしまい！
With this, Ochichi Mela's singing slot is over!
4人コラボでも歌いますのじゃ
We will also sing in a 4-person collab,
次はソフィア！
so next up is Sophia!
それじゃあおぬしら、さらばじゃー！
So then, everyone, farewell!